

# LUIS RIVAS

luisrivasinc@gmail.com | 562-507-6020 | Long Beach, CA 90805

## Summary

Capable IT experienced in helping users correct problems with computer systems, mobile devices and peripheral equipment. Knowledgeable about usability and security concerns. Skilled at working alone to investigate and fix problems.

Dependable IT with 30 years of helpdesk experience. Assist end-users with complex technical issues. Communicate complicated concepts in clear manner.

#### Skills

- Application installations
- Application support
- Technical issue analysis
- Debugging

- Troubleshooting and diagnostics
- Equipment repair
- Hardware configuration
- Software upgrades

# Experience

#### IT Specialist

11/2009 - 03/2020

Self Employment | Long Beach, CA

- Responded to assistance requests from users and directed individuals through basic troubleshooting tasks.
- Removed malware and viruses from laptops and desktop systems using specialized software.
- Observed system functioning and entered commands to test different areas of operations.
- Consulted via telephone to understand user problems, run through testing scripts and ask probing questions to locate root causes.
- Disassembled computer systems to troubleshoot and resolve hardware issues.
- Reviewed current hardware and software and recommended modifications to increase system speed.
- Installed and configured printers and scanners, resetting default device passwords to prevent cyber attacks.

#### **Computer Programmer**

01/2005 - 01/2009

RC SystemsInc | Los Angeles, CA

- Developed databases, web forms and file systems to fill different needs.
- Acted as subject matter expert when resolving computer programming issues.
- Developed production, test and beta websites using various software programs.

#### IT Technical Support

02/2004 - 02/2006

Garza Express | Los Angeles, CA

- Updated software versions with patches and new installations to close security loopholes and protect users.
- Removed malware and viruses from laptops and desktop systems using specialized software.
- Installed and configured printers and scanners, resetting default device passwords to prevent cyber attacks.
- Disassembled computer systems to troubleshoot and resolve hardware issues.

### **IT Technical Support**

01/2001 - 11/2005

Money Gram | Los Angeles, CA

• Installed and configured printers and scanners, resetting default device passwords to prevent

cyber attacks.

• Set up new desktop systems and configured laptops for incoming employees, loading required software and server permissions.

Education and Training

**Bachelor of Science**: Computer Science CSS | GUATEMALA

12/1997